I demand an explanation, sir.
Answer me.
Answers are a response
to questions, Vicky.
Demands are either accepted
or rejected.
Which I have already done.
Why didn't you do it yourself?
Why did you reject my thesis
in an email to the vice chancellor?
It's a question this time, sir.
You must answer.
Personal development.
Character building.
Building the nation.
Remember what it means?
Of course.
If you hadn't rejected it...
Then the primary subject of my thesis
would have been these RSS slogans.
Slogans?
This is your problem, Vicky.
I asked you the meaning.
And you're giving me references.
That too wrong ones.
These are not slogans.
These are the three veins
of the Sangh.
Each swayamsevak's patriotism...
runs through them.
I had taught you all this
three years ago.
I had taught you something else too.
Do you remember or...
I remember.
But until these three things
are done
the work will be incomplete.
It has nothing to do with
the rejection of my thesis.
It does.
I'm tired of trying to develop you
as a person.
But you...
You couldn't build your character.
These are not my signatures.
And yet you mentioned me
as your guide in your thesis.
I know why.
Because the path
this guide showed you
you were going
in the opposite direction.
That's why...
That's why
I got your thesis rejected.
And I'll do it ten more times.
Do whatever you want.
"Ekam sat, vipr bahuda vadanti".
There is only one Truth, sir.
But wise men believe
that there are many truths.
This is something
you've taught me.
There might be multiple paths
leading to the truth.
But if the destination is Truth
then it's our responsibility to
remove all the obstacles on the way.
Our paths are very different, sir.
There was only one obstacle
on my path.
This signature.
I have removed that too.
Did I do something wrong?
Tell me, sir.
What was my mistake?
And if I have done something wrong,
prove it.
If you can prove it,
I'll back off.
If you can't prove it...
then you're no one to stop me
in this independent nation.
Who are you?
I'm not stopping you, Vicky.
I'm rectifying my mistake.
Because you are my mistake.
Sir!
- Stop filming.
- Sir!
Sir.
This is not your classroom where
you can just say class dismissed.
The conversation has just started.
Vicky.
Stop this circus.
Leave right now.
I want to leave, sir.
But he has rejected my thesis.
Along with my thesis...
he wants to block
my new way of thinking.
It's your bad luck, sir.
You can use your power
to stop the publication of my thesis
but not my voice.
Is this a film shoot?
- Stop the camera.
- Why, sir?
Why should we stop?
You're doing all this to protect
your beloved RSS.
- Did you record that?
- Yes, ma'am.
Show me.
- Share it with me, okay.
- Okay.
May I come in, sir?
Sir, I'm Vicky Hegde.
Your student.
Sir, I want to write a thesis
on the history of the RSS.
On the hundred years of the RSS.
And no one better to guide me
on this topic but you.
Will you please help me?
Do you even know
who established the Sangh?
Dr. Keshavrao Baliram Hedgewar.
Born 1889, April.
Are you writing a thesis
or making a hodgepodge?
It's not a hodgepodge.
It's a 12-course meal.
And I can assure you, sir
my thesis will reveal
a lot of hidden truths
about the history of the RSS.
(students protesting)
Sir, you're fighting against
your professor and the Sangh.
An educational institute
is dedicated to Goddess Saraswati...
Please tell us why.
Both of us worship Saraswati,
the goddess of knowledge.
But no matter
how beautiful the idol is
if it's covered in dust
then it can't be worshipped.
What does that have to do
with the Sangh?
Many swayamsevaks
are propagating their ideologies
in schools, colleges...
They're trying to fool us too.
They've been lying to us for years.
Every time new India has
raised their voice...
they've been systematically silenced.
What exactly is your thesis about?
The truth about the RSS is my thesis.
The truth they've hidden for years.
But I'm going to unmask the truth.
Your thesis has been rejected.
What do you have to say about that?
No one can reject my thesis now.
And no one can silence me.
What about your own teacher
slapping you?
He didn't just slap me.
He slapped every Indian citizen
who dared to seek the truth. Got it?
But my thesis...
...will expose the RSS.
The RSS is
an anti-national organisation.
How can you call the RSS--
Do they even know what
anti-national means?
A group that has not picked up
weapons in the last 100 years.
They are...
Anyway...
And you?
Why are you surprised?
Prabha, in life either you win
or you learn a lesson.
And there's only one lesson
in our life.
Don't get too used
to the good times.
It'll eventually leave you in tears.
Let me see.
I'll put some ointment at night.
It'll be fine by morning.
Prabha.
So many years of pain.
Can it be healed overnight?
When we carry some pain
for years...
Unknowingly, we make it our own.
We help them grow with care.
Then it doesn't hurt so much.
On time.
Very good.
Shut the door.
The path you've chosen, Vicky...
You need to keep an open mind for that.
But behind closed doors.
Start training now.
You'll find it handy later on.
Okay?
Thank you, Vicky.
One needs guts to do
what you did. Right?
That one slap made you
shake up the entire system.
Ma'am, one doesn't need guts
to get slapped.
Only jaws.
- Ipshita!
- Yes.
Where's the thesis index
I'd asked for?
Whether my instructions are
written or spoken...
Don't you ever cut them.
Yes, ma'am.
So, Vicky, you should keep
an open mind now. Right?
Because until now
you were under Nadkarni's wing.
He narrates the written truth
quite well. I mean...
With all due respect.
But once you're under my wing
you'll learn that truth
doesn't need to be narrated.
Narratives need to be turned
into truth.
Noted, ma'am.
By the way, which one is your wing?
Right wing or--
Left is always right.
And ma'am, thank you.
For making my "slap video" go viral.
Good night.
Ma'am, he thinks you made
the video go viral. Meaning?
Meaning he doesn't
only have an open mind.
But a sharp mind too.
Hey!
What?
Vicky, please don't get involved
with them.
They're supporting you now
because you're in the news.
When you fall none of them
will come to your rescue.
So, Saara, you're confident
that I'll fall.
I'm not going to fall.
And even if I do
these people will pull me up.
Got it?
Prof. Nadkarni always said...
If we fall
it makes a huge difference
who helps up get back up.
Maybe it made a difference to him.
Makes no difference to me.
Saara, I need to reach my goal.
I don't care if the car that takes me
there is red, saffron or green--
It does make a difference, Vicky!
They're not right.
Whoever takes me to my destination
is right for me.
Got it?
Mumbai Institute of Arts and Economics
student, Vicky's actions today
has sent shockwaves
that will be felt in Delhi too.
Viral video sensation, Vicky Hegde,
one slap and a revolution.
On social media, #JusticeforVicky
and #MumbaiCollegeCrisis are trending.
The video where Vicky...
talks about removing
the dust has millions of views.
Students have launched a digital war.
Universities across the world
have shown support for Vicky.
Is it safe for just one student to go
against such a big organisation?
Vicky said he'll not back off.
(students protesting)
Look, we should restrict this here.
No one will gain anything by washing
dirty linen in public.
Vicky, you want respect.
I'll give it you.
I assure you.
Nadkarni, you have problems
with the camera?
I'll give you the assurance.
No cameras. No CCTV.
Closed rooms.
Nadkarni, Vicky,
do you agree?
We'll decide everything here.
Ready?
Okay.
It's decided then.
Let's finish this now.
Ma'am, we have a problem.
VC is convincing him
for a closed-door meeting.
He'll compromise.
Didn't I tell you to send
more people to the fountain?
Did you?
Ma'am, you're not listening to me.
He'll give in.
Didn't you hear him
clearly yesterday?
If I've understood him even a little
then he'll not let anything happen
behind closed doors.
You know why, Ipshita?
Because he's a bomb.
And bombs only know one thing.
Boom!
Vicky is here.
(indistinct chatter)
Sir.
We'll talk behind closed doors.
But sir, I have five questions.
If you answer those,
I'll take my thesis back.
Where are you going, sir?
The class is about to begin.
Sir, what's the hurry?
Hold on.
Sir.
Sir, please stop.
There's one more class
you must teach.
Sir! Sir!
One minute, sir! One minute!
Looks like you're in a rush.
Sir, you call yourself my guide.
My guru.
I've asked you five questions.
And if you can answer them...
I'll disappear.
But if you fail to answer even
one question...
Then the truth about the RSS
will come out in the open.
My question is...
Do you accept this challenge?
What happened, sir?
Why are you so quiet?
Why aren't you saying anything?
Take this megaphone.
Talk through this.
Anyway, you are a mouthpiece
for the RSS.
Do you see this Nataraj idol, Vicky?
Can you all see this Nataraj idol?
What is under his feet?
Most people often think
it's a child.
It's not a child.
It's a dwarf demon.
Apasmarasur.
A symbol of ignorance
and your memory loss.
That which makes you
forget everything.
Dignity, knowledge, education!
Sometimes when the student...
becomes a demon like Apasmarasur...
then the teacher has to become
like Nataraj.
You said I don't have the answers.
I do have the answers.
I always did.
But do you have the patience to
understand the answers?
I have a lot of patience.
But we have waited for this
for 75 years.
Let's settle it today.
What do you say?
Okay.
Ask away.
Right here.
In front of everyone.
Great!
Alright.
So, here's my question number one.
The Sangh that Prof. Nadkarni
is such a huge fan of...
Their claim to fame is...
that they've been banned thrice.
In fact, after Independence
the Indian government
had immediately banned them.
Am I right, sir?
In 1948, after Gandhi's assassination.
My question is very simple, sir.
If the organisation that was banned
by the Indian government
is not anti-national,
then what is it?
Tell me, sir.
You said the Indian government
had banned RSS.
You are right.
But...
if the ban was justified...
then why was it lifted?
What does it prove?
Vicky.
We didn't kill Gandhi.
I have a question for you.
Who was the first person
to mourn Gandhi's death?
Guruji, there's a telegram
from the Delhi office.
Gandhi is no more.
Godse has...
Ram!
This is very unfortunate
for the nation.
Halt all programmes.
The country is in mourning.
The Sangh will also be in mourning
for 13 days.
"Om shanti om!"
- "Om shanti om!"
- "Om shanti shanti!"
(radio playing)
Guruji, they're burning Brahmins
down in Pune.
The fire will spread to Nagpur soon.
We are concerned about your safety.
We'll give them a fitting reply.
(all agreeing)
Quiet!
Calm down.
They are our people too.
They've lost their way.
We'll not respond to violence
with more violence.
We too believe in non-violence.
Guruji.
Orders from higher authority.
I have to arrest you.
If my arrest brings peace
to the nation
then I'm ready.
Stop, Guruji!
(indistinct chatter)
Please break your vow of silence,
Mr. Golwalkar.
Godse has admitted
that he was a member of the RSS.
And the Sangh taught him
how to fire a gun.
We just need a signature.
Assume that you gave the orders.
Godse had left the Sangh
many years back.
He wants pure politics.
And we want culture.
The world will not understand
this technicality.
The government believes
that crime festered in your backyard.
If you don't take responsibility
we'll destroy the Sangh completely.
The Sangh is not a building
that you can destroy.
It's a school of thought.
It exists today.
And it'll still exist in India
after 100 years.
"Truth alone triumphs".
Your Honour, I don't repent
anything I've done.
One more thing.
I had quit the Sangh
a long time back.
Because I wanted to be active
in politics.
That was my own decision.
The act you are labelling
as crime...
The honour of carrying it out
is mine alone.
And I'm proud of it!
Long live "Akandh Bharat",
undivided India!
- Long live!
So, according to you
the RSS had nothing to do
with Gandhi's assassination.
Please tell us the truth.
Gandhi's spirit will sob
hearing your lies.
Vicky, you're talking about Gandhi.
Do you know what he thought
about the RSS?
- Left, right, left.
RASHTRIYA SWAYAMSEVAK SANGH
BRANCH - WARDHA MAHARASHTRA
You've been a part
of the Congress yourself.
Then why didn't you establish
the Sangh with the Congress?
If you'd done that
the Congress could have
shared the blessings.
I had tried.
With Dr. Paranjape.
But...
We didn't succeed.
Because of Laxmi,
the goddess of wealth?
It was never about the money.
It was a difference of principles.
I believe the nation doesn't need
only politics.
We need to build it
on character.
Without any character, independence
would be reduced to an empty voice.
It can still be heard.
But it would lack strength.
It is a very difficult path.
The path of the truth
is always difficult.
You already know that.
July, 1949.
The ban was lifted.
Unconditionally...
Without any strings.
You tell me, Vicky.
Why?
Answer me.
Because the Indian government
couldn't prove beyond doubt
that the RSS is anti-nationalist.
Right?
Exactly.
Thank you.
Now think calmly.
If the ban was justified
would the Indian government
lift the ban?
Banning the RSS
was considered ethically
and legally wrong.
In spite of this,
the RSS has shown patriotism.
Choosing non-violence over violence.
Now you tell me.
Is this behaviour anti-nationalist?
Or is it the definition
of a true nationalist?
Wow, sir!
That's amazing!
It'll be great fun to participate
in a debate with you.
Can you calm down a bit, sir?
Because when you get worked up
you tend to slap people.
What I mean to say is...
Don't shoot the messenger.
Okay, sir?
Things like debate
are part of Western thinking.
Debate means argument.
India believes in "samvad"
that's constructive discussion.
That's what we believe in.
I have taught you this.
Words and weapons roll off
an Indian's tongue with equal ease.
Do you need more clarifications
to your first question?
Or you can ask your next question.
Okay. Okay.
Let's give him the due advantage.
The RSS had nothing to do with
Gandhi's assassination.
But sir...
What about 1975?
Emergency.
According to the order issued by
the Government of India
all news mediums must
seek approval before publishing.
Who is Girish Nadkarni?
It's me.
Come with us.
We're here to arrest you.
Father!
(indistinct chatter)
When the entire country
was burning...
- Where are you taking him?
- Father!
- Let go!
When the entire opposition
was in jail...
Your leaders were writing letters
to Indira Gandhi.
"Please... Let us go."
"We'll not get involved in politics."
Sir, this is my second question.
Isn't it true?
When it was time to fight
the Sangh had taken the knee.
What a shame!
What a tragedy!
You read the letters, Vicky.
Not the thoughts behind them.
You think it was fear?
Thankfully during
Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj's time
there was no social media.
Otherwise these so-called Leftists...
If they were present
and got to know
that Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj
is going to meet Afzal Khan
they would've made hashtags.
"Will Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj
bend the knee?"
It would have gone viral.
But Vicky...
When a tiger pounces to kill
its enemy
it first takes a step back.
At that time, lakhs of swayamsevaks
were in jail.
Their families were out
on the streets.
Helpless.
A general's duty
is not just to fight.
It is also to protect his soldiers.
Father.
Everyone is saying you've done
something wrong.
The police are saying you're an enemy
of the country.
When the authorities are scared
of being questioned
they turn the people who ask
the questions into enemies.
Don't be scared.
Never be afraid.
You need the courage of a swayamsevak
to tell the truth.
Remember that.
Sulochana Nadkarni.
GIRISH NADKARNI
Mother, what's wrong?
Your father is no more.
That was strategy.
To ensure thousands of fathers
could return home.
So that those children
didn't become orphans.
You call the RSS's action tragedy.
Whereas it is the RSS
that saved this democracy.
When I was in jail
during the Emergency
I observed the swayamsevaks.
When we were all put in jail.
I saw how disciplined you were.
Your sacrifice and your service
changed my mind.
I noticed how,
even in captivity
you set aside ideas of caste and creed
and remained united.
I realised the future of the nation
is secure in your hands.
Your contribution to the fight
against the Emergency
would be etched in gold
on the pages of history.
The maximum number of protestors
to be jailed were RSS workers.
Without your cadres
and your organisation
this revolution could never
be successful.
You have sacrificed yourself
for the sake of democracy.
The nation will
forever be in your debt.
Emotional blackmail.
These are all stories.
He has no proof.
Sir, if you're so honest
and if you have the guts
then answer my third question.
Year 1992.
Babri Masjid.
What was the strategy?
That was a crime.
Do you have the guts
to answer my question?
What's going on?
Sir, are you okay?
Show's over.
Everybody get back to class.
Come on.
Ma'am does your wing
always interrupt?
You'd lost
after asking your five questions.
Remember, I saved you.
Let's go.
Ma'am.
Vicky is losing it.
He's digressing from the topic.
Wrong place, wrong time.
It was the right time.
But the place was wrong.
He is not lost, Ipshita.
He is expanding.
The boy has a lot of fire.
And fire needs oxygen.
What do you mean?
This topic is too big
for the university campus.
It needs to be on prime time.
Hey babe, how are you?
You know the coverage
of Mrs. Roy's books was incredible.
Too good.
Now, listen.
I have gold for you.
Our previous agendas
were not successful.
That's why we couldn't topple
the government.
There's a very important topic.
We can expose the relationship
between the government and the RSS
for political benefit.
We can brew hatred in the hearts
of the citizens.
We'll bring about change
with the power of the youth.
Another thing...
We have a professor there.
Pallavi Menon.
Contact her and tell her
to help all our people
in the college.
The narrative should be set.
This Prof. Nadkarni of the RSS...
Assassinate his character.
Give political support
to the student movement.
Every person should be forced
to take sides.
Our side.
Mr. Aditya Rao.
I'm surprised.
It took you so much time.
I'm giving you a chance
to be the face
of the biggest debate of the year.
Student versus teacher.
Left wing versus right wing.
Student Vicky Hegde.
- Teacher Prof. Dr. Gopal Nadkarni.
- Correct!
My professor.
Your ex-professor
who'll come to the debate--
Firstly, this guy...
The stunt that he has pulled...
he'll never come.
Listen to me.
Vicky Hegde has already
been convinced
by my old classmate, Pallavi.
He will come.
And you bring Nadkarni.
The debate is yours.
Ms. Kavya Rawat, you've stopped him
from coming to this newsroom
because he is from the RSS.
And today you're inviting him
to this newsroom
because he is from the RSS.
How convenient!
I'll talk to him.
But don't play the ticker.
Don't give me that look.
Been there and done that. Okay?
I'll talk to him
and if it's a yes, okay.
I'm telling you...
Okay?
Play the ticker.
It's a news channel.
If there's no promotion,
there won't be any commotion.
Bharat Express presents
the biggest debate of the year.
Monday Battle Royale.
This Monday at 12 noon.
Can the teacher answer when the student
bombards him with questions?
Don't forget to tune in.
Exclusively on Bharat Express.
(students protesting)
The administration of the Mumbai
Institute of Arts and Economics
have been gheraoed.
While the students protest violently,
the faculty also seem divided...
...in their opinion.
An absolute gridlock at CSMT.
Protestors have occupied the tracks.
Now the lifeline of the city
has come to a complete standstill.
We have to be on high alert
in all these locations.
Use force to stop, not to hurt.
(students protesting)
The area around the university has been
turned into a virtual fortress.
Several clashes between the police
and the protestors have been reported.
Police Commissioner has urged everyone
to maintain peace.
But Vicky's supporters aren't ready
to back off.
Would the police have to use force?
The situation is rife with tension.
(students protesting)
Are you students or politicians?
Why aren't you in college
and out here blocking traffic?
Are you asking us
whether we are politicians or not?
Can you ask Prof. Nadkarni
the same question?
Then tell us
who is the real politician?
Who is consciously injecting
the system with his own ideology?
The citywide chaos
that you have created seems...
...so performative and directionless.
Our professor was the one
who created the scene.
We have simply expanded our reach.
So the entire nation has to listen.
We're on the streets
because we have nothing to hide.
Vicky is gaining support from
universities across the world.
(students protesting)
You've put on weight, sethji.
Put the bag in the car's boot.
Let your boss know
the job will be done.
Look, Prof. Nadkarni.
I have a lot of respect for you.
But this is about
the university's reputation.
I've been constantly getting calls
from the trustees.
They want you to formally apologise.
An apology letter.
You can say you were angry and...
And you took it out on the student
by mistake.
Simple.
You talk about respect
and then you take it away.
Apology letter?
What is the apology for?
For telling the truth?
Or for holding the mirror
to this ill-mannered student?
Stop being so stubborn, Gopal.
We're in the age of social media.
Here the truth is not
what is actually true.
Truth is what can be seen.
That is how media's film works.
And right now...
You are looking like a villain
in this film.
Maybe I'm the villain in your film.
But did you know?
I was the one
who suggested the apology letter.
You'll be retiring in two years.
We're talking
about your pension, Gopal.
Think about it.
Thank you for your concern.
You're not the villain in my film.
Then what am I?
Please tell me.
What do you think of me?
I don't think about you at all.
Mr. Nadkarni, we have to
protect our funding.
Don't make me force my hand.
Please sign the letter.
Come on.
This apology letter reminded me
of something else.
Then you can become a "Maafiveer",
apologist-hero, like your own hero.
The apology letter
you're talking about...
Please do some research first.
You'll understand.
There's a reason why
a person is hailed a hero.
As far as signing goes...
Let me tell you a story.
When it was time to pass the bar exam,
to become a lawyer...
the British had given him a paper
in London...
to write he'd never say
anything against the British.
Only then would he be allowed
to pass the bar.
They wanted him to sign it.
Or else...
Guess what your "maafiveer"
and my hero had said.
This.
That's what he did.
I'll make some tea.
Prabha.
Please sit.
Oh what fun!
The professors in our university.
They're very secular.
But they were focussed
on violence today.
So, instead of them,
I invoked Gandhi today.
What?
Non-cooperation movement.
They asked me to give up
on my principles.
So, I gave it to them.
Resignation letter.
Freshen up.
I'll get some tea for you.
Prabha.
I'll help you around the house
from tomorrow.
Will he answer
all of his student's questions?
Forget about answers,
the teacher has run off.
He has tendered his resignation.
Why?
If I were in Vicky's place,
I'd slapped Nadkarni back.
We don't want his resignation.
We want a public apology.
I want to ask
what has the RSS ever done.
We can't find you anywhere
in the history books.
Let me ask you a simple question.
During the struggle
for independence...
When the entire country
was in agony...
When so many people were
sent to jail...
There was bloodbath everywhere...
Where was the RSS?
Where were you hiding?
In some room in Nagpur?
We weren't hiding.
We were active.
For you, struggle means
either going to jail
or featuring in newspapers.
There are different levels
of struggle.
In the mind,
through speech and through actions.
Are you aware?
That's your way of thinking.
You are confusing us with semantics.
You are confused as it is.
We're trying to explain things
to you.
Dr. Keshav Hedgewar.
He is respectfully referred to as
Doctor saab.
Really sorry about this.
My two P's, professionalism
and passion.
I always get mixed up
in these.
There's a third P.
Psychosis.
Don't mix that too.
I am crazy.
Guilty as charged.
But I can't help myself
when it comes to the truth.
I have learnt it from you, sir.
Always stand with the truth.
I haven't always agreed with you.
And I won't.
Sir, you're my professor too.
You've been my teacher.
Of course, I haven't agreed on
everything you've said and I won't.
Please try to understand why
I'm doing this.
Sir...
Every time you spoke
about the country...
Everything you said...
It would touch us.
I'd always thought...
These thoughts should be shared
with the nation and the youth.
Ma'am.
I think this is...
the right time for sir to...
The national debate has been
scheduled for Monday.
The Sangh doesn't have to justify
itself to anyone.
Aditya.
Right, sir.
I understand and I...
But try to see it
from my perspective.
It's his job to make empty noises.
Not mine.
He wants to create a scene, let him.
I'm not part of his circus.
But you are his teacher.
He considers you his guru.
And you treat him like a son.
So, he's creating a scene.
Who's responsible for
bringing him back to the class?
(indistinct chatter)
Hello, Mr. Vicky.
Yes?
I am Sohrab.
Your well-wisher has sent me.
I don't need any well-wisher.
A lion hunts alone.
But when there's a forest fire...
even the lion burns.
I'm only here to make sure
the fire doesn't spread
to your home.
This is my fight.
And I'm not a sell-out.
Got it?
That's what we want too.
Don't sell out.
Thank you for your visit.
In our line of work
very few people say thank you.
Whether you fight
with or without our help...
As long as the result is victory...
I'm cool.
Please remember one thing.
My friends never lose.
Got it?
Why are you trying to be a hero?
Can't you see what's going on?
Vicky, this is not a debate.
It's a riot.
People have come to your home.
Who was that man?
What did he want?
Saara, if I keep quiet too
there'd be no difference between
them and me.
Somebody has to cast
the first stone.
But why you, Vicky?
If not me, then who?
Then who, Saara?
The digital warriors on both sides
are prepared for the battle on Monday.
This battle is not confined within
the college campus anymore.
It has become
the spirit of the internet
and a fight for identity.
Is this a fair debate?
Or has it turned into a televised
media trial of a young man's career?
It's not just going to be a debate
but a live chargesheet.
Will Nadkarni be able to face
these pointed questions?
- Down with Nadkarni!
They threw ink at you!
Prabha, history as witness...
whenever anyone tries
to soil the saffron
history is written
with the same ink.
Let there be 500 questions.
I will answer
every last one of them.
We're looking at
a student-teacher contract
that has been shredded by
a single physical blow.
Vicky Hegde has effectively turned
his research into a weapon
against the very system
that has tried to silence him.
He didn't just target
an organisation.
He targeted a mindset...
This boy isn't from Mumbai,
I've seen him.
Lay off the drugs.
He is a student leader from Mumbai.
Wait, let me show you.
...will no longer be confined
to the classroom or the library.
Bharat Express has announced
a special segment.
Monday Battle Royale:
Guru versus student.
A very important day.
A very important debate.
With all eyes on Vicky
and Prof. Nadkarni.
(students protesting)
There's only one question
on everyone's mind.
When will
this extraordinary debate start?
Who will win this debate?
The student or the teacher?
Questions will be asked with
an open mind.
Will Prof. Nadkarni be able
to answer with the same openness?
What will happen here today?
Will Prof. Nadkarni be able
to answer Vicky's questions?
Everyone is waiting eagerly for
Prof. Nadkarni and Vicky.
There's heavy police posting here.
(song playing)
Where is he?
Where is Nadkarni?
Kavya, the professor
is not answering his phone.
I think he's ghosting us.
The show begins in 10 minutes.
If he is not here by then
what will we telecast?
An empty screen?
The sponsors will chop my head off.
Send a camera team to his house.
Break the door if you have to.
Go!
Go right now!
The class will begin now
because the professor is here.
Let's go.
Everybody ready?
We go live in...
Three.
Two.
Go.
And roll!
Either the W's of journalism.
Or the Night of Doom.
Ministers in Parliament.
Or the questions
of our favourite Vicky.
They share one thing in common.
That's five questions.
And the five questions of
Judgement Day are...
How did they live their life
on earth?
How did they utilise their youth?
How did they earn their wealth?
How did they spend their wealth?
And what did they do
with their knowledge?
Just like this,
five questions...
were asked by our govt.
to the opposition in May, 2024.
First question.
Triple Talaq.
Second question.
UCC: Uniform Civil Code.
Third Question.
Surgical strikes.
Fourth question.
Ram Mandir.
Fifth question.
Article 370.
This is how
questions will be asked here today.
Most importantly,
questions will be asked to
Rashtriya Swayamsevak Sangh
that's RSS.
We all know that the Sangh
has a few principles.
One of which is not participating
in debates.
And we totally respect that.
But the situation
is a little different here.
As things transpired...
The questions were directed to
Vicky's thesis guide and mentor
Dr. Prof. Gopal Nadkarni.
There's something very interesting
happening here.
If it were a five-day cricket match,
today would have been the third day.
And it were a one-day match,
then I would have said...
Welcome to the live telecast
of second innings.
What happens
before the second innings?
You know what happens.
Here are the highlights
from the first innings.
Have a look.
So, here's my question number one.
The Sangh that Prof. Nadkarni
is such a huge fan of...
Their claim to fame is...
that they've been banned thrice.
In 1948,
after Gandhi's assassination.
If the organisation that was banned
by the Indian government
is not anti-national,
then what is it?
We didn't assassinate Gandhi.
July, 1949.
The ban was lifted.
Unconditionally...
Without any strings.
Sir, this is my second question.
What about 1975?
Emergency?
When the entire opposition
was in jail...
Your leaders were writing
letters to Indira Gandhi.
That was strategy.
A general's duty
is not just to fight.
It is also to protect his soldiers.
BHARAT
EXPRESS
Our constitution
believes in free speech.
If asking questions
is free speech
then answering them
is also free speech.
I'd like to tell the audience
that both Vicky and Prof. Nadkarni
have refused to a judge's panel
or any kind of polling.
I'd like to know why.
I've asked him questions
for which he doesn't have an answer.
That's the end of the story.
Then how would you decide
whether you agree with his answers?
Sir, do you want to take this?
In "the Mahabharata", King Drupad...
Drupad?
Guys...
That's Draupadi's dad.
Drupad, Draupadi's father...
wanted to slay Dronacharya.
He raised his son, Dhrishtadyumna,
to defeat Drona.
He was like our very own Vicky.
He knew it would be no easy task.
He went to Drona and said...
"Please take me in as your disciple
so that I can slay you."
Dronacharya, even after
knowing this...
... taught him everything.
That's a teacher's responsibility.
We trust our students.
Even when they try to destroy us.
Vicky has been my student.
Although he's used my teachings
against me.
But I still believe
if I give him the correct answers
he'll accept them in all honesty.
It was not only your request.
But the fact that there's still
some truth left in Vicky
is what brought me here.
Sir!
When this "Dhrist-guy" fought Drona,
who won?
You want to take that, Mr. Vicky?
Drona dropped his weapon
believing in a lie
and started meditating
on the battlefield.
That's when Dhrishtadyumna
beheaded his teacher, Dronacharya.
Aditya.
Start with the questions...
...before these two take out
their swords.
Ask the questions.
Fast!
In this epic battle
between truth and lies
Vicky will now ask his third, fourth
and final question.
Professor...
Here's my third question
for your Sangh, your RSS.
Babri Masjid!
December, 1992.
I want to ask all of you a question.
Can anyone tell me
who demolished Babri?
You?
You've been an active volunteer
of the RSS.
Was the destruction of the Babri Masjid
a pre-planned conspiracy?
Please answer
and let's keep it simple.
Just give us a yes or a no.
Speak up, professor.
If the RSS is a peaceful,
charitable organisation
then why did its members
climb the dome?
Why were the walls broken?
Please tell us, professor.
I'll ask you
the most important question.
Do you, in any way, justify the actions
of the RSS committed on the day
of the demolition of the Babri Masjid?
Just say yes or no!
I don't support any of the violent acts
of that day, Vicky.
Great!
Then say it.
Admit it that the RSS
committed a crime.
That the RSS demolished Babri Masjid
and the RSS is violent.
Just say it!
The RSS did not demolish any mosque.
There were protests
in front of Babri's structure.
But the structure didn't break...
when kar sevaks touched it.
It broke when
this nation's majority's trust
was broken.
Aditya, please pull up the slide.
Yes, sir.
Play the slide.
Take a look.
This section in the middle.
According to British records,
it's called 'Chhathi'.
Birthplace.
We didn't get permission to enter
our God's house.
What did our ancestors do?
They prayed outside
on this "Ram Chabutra".
Come rain or sunshine...
They waited for centuries.
Staring at that wall.
Hoping that one day
they'll be allowed inside.
They followed the law.
They waited patiently.
You're mourning the loss
of a 500-year-old building.
What about our faith...
That had been waiting forever
for its turn?
When the legal system fails
and days become years
then patience runs out.
And when patience runs out
then neither lives are spared
nor structures.
What structure?
Why aren't you calling
it the Babri Masjid?
Are you scared?
Are you ashamed?
Or was it your great RSS's holy war?
I am not calling it a mosque...
Because there are rules in Islam
about it.
And Babri does not follow them.
"Sahih al-Bukhari " and "Sahih Muslim"
both mention this.
Don't build mosques on graves.
It's forbidden.
According to "fiqh"
mosques are not to be built
on usurped land.
It states clearly
in Ibn Qudama's "Al-Mughni ".
Is that enough?
Or do you want me to give you
page numbers like Mr. Naik?
This is emotional manipulation.
Where are the facts?
He presented the facts.
He showed the map.
Talked about the history.
But the mosque was destroyed.
What about the belief
that was broken?
So, you're justifying
the RSS's actions, right?
If it is built on usurped land,
then the mosque is not valid, Vicky.
It was built on encroached land.
Taken land.
A land which others believe
is disputed land.
Even according to
Shariat law
such a building is never
considered a mosque.
It can only be called a structure.
India's Supreme Court...
The highest legal institution
of the country...
...has acknowledged that remnants
of a temple were found underneath.
The Archaeological Survey has shown
temple pillars, "kalash", "amalkas"
and shrine platform.
In 1976
KK Muhammad had proved
there was a temple under Babri.
How can I call it a mosque?
So, you're saying all this
to justify yourself, right?
I believe in the soil
of this country.
I believe in the wise sages...
Doesn't matter
whether they're Hindu or Muslim...
The ones who preach unity
and not politics.
This is my India.
And I'll always justify
the believers of this holy land.
You say the RSS demolished
a mosque.
I am saying...
India's faith was destroyed first.
The Sangh was just the last heartbeat
of centuries old ache.
In the last 100 years, the Sangh has
only been associated with one temple.
Ramjanmabhoomi,
birthplace of Ram.
And Vicky, there are two more sites.
Great if we get them cordially.
But if we have to fight,
we are ready.
This is a matter
of the nation's belief.
Did you get it, Vicky?
Say yes or no!
Friends, at this point
we'll take a break.
Please come back for more questions
on the other side.
BHARAT
EXPRESS
VICKY'S QUESTION ON RAM JANMABHOOMI
GETS FACTS FROM NADKARNI
What comes next in this debate?
The tension keeps rising
with every heartbeat.
I've never seen anything
quite like this before.
(students protesting)
The situation has taken a turn.
The prof's answers
has divided the crowd in two.
The crowd is growing.
The police barricade
is about to break.
We'll have to wait to see
how the police handle the situation.
Now, let's get to
your biggest defense.
Social work.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The Sangh proclaims to be the world's
largest voluntary organisation.
Selfless service.
Nation building.
Sounds great, doesn't it?
But professor...
There's a loophole in your greatness.
There's no documentation
of your great work.
Isn't that strange?
You claim to be running the country.
It is not a selfless service mission.
It's a convenient mask.
A facade.
For you and your Sangh
to hide behind.
This is known as social service.
Bravo!
Prof, may I come closer to you?
Please.
One second.
And this is the RSS's contribution.
Zero!
Are you fans of Aryabhatta?
Always stuck on zero.
That's all for now.
Brilliant!
That would leave a mark.
He's right.
Anyone can build castles in the air.
Where's the proof?
You're looking at social work
through corporate lenses.
There you need to show
proof of work.
We offer sacrifices.
We don't have
a centralised database.
Because we're swayamsevaks, volunteers.
Very convenient excuse, sir.
Burden of proof
is your responsibility.
Burden of accountability
belongs to the RSS.
What does responsibility mean?
Break the word down.
Responsibility is response
and ability.
The ability to respond.
In the hour of need
the first respondent is
not a guy in black suit.
Nor in white kurta.
They wear khaki pants.
You'd have known if you travelled
across the country.
Accountability?
For what?
For the cameras?
Tell me something, Vicky.
When someone is drowning
in a flood...
Or someone is dying of hunger...
Instead of helping him
should we take a selfie first?
Should we make a show
of his helplessness
so that it can trend
on social media?
This is your selfie culture
not the Sangh's.
Wow!
That's amazing, professor!
You should have been a politician
or an actor.
Why did you become a professor?
Thing is your big words
won't work anymore.
You did exactly what
the Sangh had done.
Lots of big words
but zero proof.
Fine.
You don't have proof.
But I have a video
that I would like to show you.
Could you please play
the tsunami video for us?
Play the video.
Stop!
After the natural disaster,
the local organisation is there.
They've reached there first.
And they're already helping
the locals.
You'd reached much later
with your flag. Right?
So many people lost their lives
that day.
Old people as well as children.
Only someone who's lost their child
would understand the pain.
- Yes?
- I'm Prashant. Nadkarni...
- Sorry, it's not that kind of show.
- Ma'am, please...
No callers allowed.
I'm sorry. No, no.
I'm sorry.
Patch the call.
Ma'am, it's very important.
Please let me speak to him.
- Ma'am, please.
- Okay.
Connecting.
Okay, Prashant.
You're live.
Please speak.
Hello, I'm Prashant.
I want to say something to Vicky.
Vicky, the person you're discussing
losing a child with
had himself lost his child
during the Mumbai floods.
(chanting funeral prayers)
He couldn't save his own child.
But he still saved another child.
Aditya, the other child was me.
That great man saved my life.
Mr. Nadkarni, please forgive me.
Accept my humble reverence.
Hey, you crazy boy.
Why are you apologising?
My Dhruv didn't die that day.
Only a father died that day.
A father had taken his last breath.
But the swayamsevak
was still breathing.
His name is Prashant.
Prashant, live a long life, son.
Be very successful.
Don't lose your way.
I'm not here to discuss my life
but to talk about the Sangh.
Please play the clip.
Okay.
Guys, play the video.
The footage you see...
These are examples of when
the camera was on by mistake.
Otherwise, there's no proof
of 99% of the work done.
When God is a witness
there's no need for proof.
I had taught you three things
about the Sangh.
Have you forgotten?
First, don't make a poster
out of helplessness.
Second.
Don't earn points
for acts of service.
Third and the most important point.
Only God is a witness
to acts of service.
There's no doubt
in the swayamsevak's heart.
Only resolve.
A swayamsevak chooses
a life of service for himself.
He doesn't act out of selfish needs.
But for selfless reasons for others.
You know all this, Vicky.
Even then?
Are you unable to see
or unwilling to see?
Vicky, hope you've got the answer
to your fourth question.
Or do you still have any doubt?
I hope you're satisfied.
And if you allow
can we take a break now?
There's no need to break.
Let's continue.
Audience.
It's time for the last question.
You must be feeling sad.
As you should.
Your opposition says...
Whenever their agenda fails,
they present a card in front of us.
Can anybody tell me
what that card is?
Which card am I talking about?
It's called the victim card.
They toy with us.
But kill their own.
And they do it
for our sympathy and so that
they can emotionally manipulate us.
Vicky!
Are you going to point a finger
at a swayamsevak's death?
Easy, professor.
Aditya, is this a boxing ring
or a media newsroom?
Please tell him.
Vicky, there's no need
to be sarcastic.
Stick to the debate, okay?
Present your point, please.
Take a look.
His name was Shrinath.
He was a dedicated swayamsevak.
But guess what happened to him.
He was hacked to death.
It's a tragedy.
But was it murder?
Or a political investment?
I believe he was killed.
Why?
So that these shameless people can
earn their votes over his dead body.
You manufacture a martyr
then you weaponise the grief.
And today, professor...
you must answer our questions.
I had five questions
but everything leads to this.
This very question.
This is final question.
This is my last question to you.
This isn't about Dronacharya
believing a lie.
Nor is it about
a teacher and his student.
This is about every Indian citizen.
Every one living in India...
...whom they have lied to.
And today you must answer
for this, professor.
At any cost.
You called our sacrifice
a business, Vicky.
I'll remember that.
Play this.
Aditya, are you crazy?
We can't play something
that hasn't been vetted.
We don't know what's on it.
It could be hate speech.
It could be graphic violence.
We cannot do this, Aditya!
Will you trust your teacher
this time?
Always, sir.
Play it.
(crowd protesting)
Madam, are you from the media?
That is not Vicky Hegde.
He is lying, madam.
Vicky Hegde.
It’s a lie, madam.
Just hold on, ma'am.
What are you saying?
He is not Vicky Hegde!
Ma'am, I'll call you back.
Come with me.
Let’s go!
Okay.
Today this man,
in front of the whole world...
has maligned the character
of the RSS.
Now the country will judge
on the basis of evidence.
Not on theories.
Vicky.
This is the final answer
to your final question.
This is it.
(chanting religious slogans)
Pause.
Vicky, did you hear that?
Did you all hear that?
Did you hear what they said?
Did you hear
what those murderers said?
Do you at least agree on that?
Yes or no?
You don't have to belong
to the Sangh.
If you're an Indian citizen...
If you're a true patriot...
Then answer me this.
Does this sound
like the Sangh's slogan?
The Palakkad Case judgement.
Six out of the seven accused
were sentenced to death.
One was a minor.
Read the court records.
The killers were not
our people, Vicky.
They were political extremists.
You wanted a pattern.
Here's your pattern.
November 15, 2021.
Mambaram, Palakkad.
Sanjith.
He was travelling with his wife.
They stopped his motorbike.
And hacked the husband
in front of the wife.
Was that stage-managed martyrdom?
March, 2002.
Melur.
CK Sujeesh and P Sunil.
Double murder!
Midnight attack.
The RSS didn't pass judgement on this.
The Supreme Court did.
January 6, 2025.
Conditions upheld.
Have you heard of Dadu Singh?
Konde, Chhattisgarh.
Maoists killed him.
Why?
Because he was talking about
the country in LWE area.
You can check all this
on the internet.
Look at T Ashwini Kumar.
Look at R Rudresh in Bengaluru.
Vicky, I didn't expect this
from you.
I've taught you about all this.
Did you forget everything
so quickly?
We didn't kill Shrinath.
We lost him.
Please understand this.
The Sangh doesn't do anything
just because they want to.
The Sangh only does...
whatever is necessary
for the country.
It's been like this
for the last 100 years.
That's why the Sangh exists.
The day there is a swayamsevak
in every house...
we won't need the Sangh anymore.
When people have differences...
terror runs through their mind.
When people come together...
It's called the Sangh.
These two words oppose each other.
And you're trying to connect them.
Vicky, this is not
the Sangh's answer.
It is India's.
Of every Indian.
Now, the decision is yours, son.
(song playing)
Vicky.
(song continues)
- (all) Hail Mother India!
- Hail Mother India!
You don't look as happy
as you should be.
He knew.
He knew I had everything
on the Shrinath murder case.
I was the one who told him
about it.
Then...
How could it be his final question?
Who is he?
He is from Palakkad.
And what he's saying will
burn our entire theory to ashes.
Speak.
Madam, the boy who is on TV
is not Vicky Hegde.
I've known him since childhood.
He is Shrinath’s son.
- Shrinath?
- Yes, ma'am.
RSS worker?
Yes.
The one who was murdered?
Oh my God!
He played...
He played us all.
The environment
is a valuable resource.
(all) The environment
Trees are a source of life
and oxygen.
(all) Trees are a source of life
Class dismissed, ma'am?
Yes.
Let's go.
(song playing)
Vicky.
Mission RSS is complete.
What next?
Project "Ashtalakshmi".
That's the Seven Sisters.